

SUMIT MAHANAG



+91 9918733576 sumit.en1997@gmail.com sumit-mahanag @linkedin.com roodymike@github.com

roodymike.github.io

PROPOSITION

According to the Job description, your requirement is for a high-performing active candidate who can mold himself to be a team player, with customer centricity. I think I am a perfect candidate as my prior experience and qualifications suggest the same.

CAREER OBJECTIVE

- To better understand the needs of my clients and seek to improve my cognitive approach for mutual betterment.
- To achieve customer-centric sustainability and skills, scaling myself horizontally in the stack and vertically in the domain.

MY NEXT STEPS

- Angular, PWA.
- Full-Stack message API with Kafka and Spring (In Research).
- Flutter
- Windows 11 UI-inspired portfolio using Three.is

SKILLS Spring Boot Java Core Jenkins Cloud Foundry Spring Security DevOps

HOBBIES



EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

Bachelors in Technology

(2015 - 2019)

United Institute of Technology, Prayagraj (AKTU)
Specialization in Electrical and Electronics Engineering securing 79.83% percentile (1st Division HONS)

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Developer

(Dec 2021- till date)

Wipro Technologies, Hyderabad

- Implemented S3 Object storage for mobile logs as blob storage and Schedular service for automated cleanup and REST Endpoints to upload and download using multipart API.
- Developed an implementation to decrease storage utilization by 96%, saving huge expenses on storage servers by compressing rasterized 2d signatures using vector conversion.
- Developed DevOps Pipeline for automatic deployment, testing, code coverage analysis, static code analysis for Xamarin (not natively supported) and Spring Boot application using tools like Jenkins, PowerShell, GitLab, NUnit, JUnit, SonarQube, Grafana, Fortify, and Cloud Foundry for robust build successions every time.
- Responsible for system critical decisions for Microservices to maintain efficient load balancing, robust architecture, and maximum uptimes.
- Developed REST APIs secured with OAuth2, and Spring Security to securely
 exchange data between frontend and backend for all microservices integrating
 Splunk, Grafana, AppDynamics, JUnit, Fortify, and SonarQube with code quality
 standards and constant improvements to the system

Software Developer

(June 2019 - Dec 2021)

Wipro Technologies, Hyderabad

- Developed Full-Stack messaging application using Spring boot, Red Hat AMQ, HTML5, and Xamarin resulting in reduced server downtime and data loss, also the architecture's performance improved by 12%.
- Applied automation for projects to help mitigate the manual work, done by other developers, resulting in increased operational efficiency by 8%.
- Worked as a full-time Xamarin Forms developer implementing log analysis, fixing defects, bugs, and research stories, improving system stability, and reduction in defect count by 50%.

Freelance Developer

(Aug 2016 - Feb 2019)

Prayagraj

 Developed, deployed, scaled, and monitored Web and Mobile Applications for small-scale businesses using Linux, AWS, Cloudflare, HTML, Flutter, and Adobe Illustrator resulting in increased revenue for customers and their satisfaction.

Intern (June 2018 – Aug 2018)

HAL, Lucknow

- Got experience in Avionics, ERP, and system design.
- Helped improve and understand the aspects of system design and customer satisfaction implementing Kaizen.

ENDORSED PROJECTS

Open-Source Messaging API

Developer. Tester, Maintainer

 Implemented Spring, Red Hat AMQ as a robust and efficient replacement to the existing Kazzing library, improving performance by 12%, and reducing server load, unresponsiveness, and data loss.

Vector Image Compression Algorithm

Developer, Tester, Maintainer

- Implemented PoTrace to convert rasterized 2d, 2-bit image to vector image using contours
 resulting in a 96% decrease in storage usage, implying huge cost savings required for
 storage servers.
- Awarded "Above and Beyond" awards for the efforts

ACHIEVEMENTS / AWARDS

- Work beyond duty awarded by clients at Wipro Technologies
- Excellence awards by clients at Wipro Technologies